about me

full name: Bashar Mengana

age: 31

home: Stockholm, Sweden

email: contact@basharmengana.com
website: basharmengana.com/resume

phone number: +46703794381

address: Ringvägen 151A, 11631 Stockholm, Sweden

driving license: yes birthday: 19880126

total work experience: 6 years 2 months

elevator pitch: A truly full stack web developer with a great team sprit and an unsaturated hunger for service design, devops, team

development and Al.

spoken languages: swedish, english, arabic, german

interests

coding, plants, travelling, architecture, art, landscapes, building things, ai, gym

skills

front end: html/javascript/css(bem)/typescript, sass, design systems(material-ui/semantic-ui), build tools, react16+, testing (jest/enzyme)

back end: python, express/node.js, package manager, aws services, rest, authentication/authorization, nosql (dynamodb), sql (postgresql), unit/integration testing

devops: gitlab-ci, serverless framework, terraform, aws cloudformation, docker, kubernetes, ~linux, terminal, aws, ~heroku, infrastructure monitoring (datadog)

service design: user journey, personas, double diamond process, service blueprint, user research, empathy/territory maps

way of working: build-measure-learn loop, lean startup, scrum/sprint, hypothesis-driven development, team development

education

school: Royal Institute of Technology / Kungliga Tekniska

Högskolan

degree: Master of Science / Civilingenjör

city: Stockholm

education completed: yes

time period: 2008/07 - 2013/07

total education: 5 years

work experience

full stack web developer

company: Scania

time period: 2017/06 - Now

total work experience: 2 years 3 months

short description: Full stack web developer in a small team of five, with additional responsibilities in user research and devops. The team creates a service that aims to 1) improve driving behavior of truck drivers, 2) reduce wear and tear of vehicles, by engaging drivers in improving their driving style through gamification. We use methods from the lean startup theory (e.g. build-measure-learn loop, MVP, hypothesis-driven development).

stack:

- **front end**: react16+, typescript, react-redux, javascript/html/css(bem), sass, jest/enzyme, material-ui
- back end: python, java, aws lambda, step functions, aws dyanmodb, aws sqs, aws kms, aws sns, aws secret store, aws s3, aws cloudfront, aws cloudlog, monitoring
- **devops**: gitlab-ci, serverless framework/terraform, aws cloudformation, datadog, aws cloudlog
- way of working: mvp (minimum viable product) development process, lean startup / build-measure-learn loop, hypothesis-driven development, jira/trello/sprint

service designer

company: Scania

time period: 2016/06 - 2017/06 total work experience: 1 year

short description: Researched and helped improve the onboarding process of a fleet management tool. I conducted interviews with our users and salesmen; designed user stories, empathy maps, territory maps and personas in a team of four service designers. We also studied how the fleet management tool was sold to find pain points and opportunities, and did lightweight MVP's to evaluate concepts quickly - and we weren't afraid to throw ideas in the bin if they didn't fly.

stack: personas, user stories, empathy maps, territory maps, double diamond process, storytelling, business model canvas(bmc), mvp(minimum viable product), journey mapping, user shadowing, user diaries/probes, service blueprint, prototyping

product owner

company: Scania

time period: 2014/09 - 2016/06

total work experience: 1 year 9 months

short description: Responsible for the product backlog of a fleet management - iOS and Android - app, and the team's vision and mission. I worked closely with other product owners to help define the future of our product portfolio. My scrum master and I made sure the team was healthy by working in areas such as team happiness, resilience, and growth.

stack: product backlog, scrum, sprints, google sprints, retrospectives, jira, automated testing, feature toggling, migration from monolith, sprint planning, certified product owner, certified scrumaster, scrum of scrum, product owner forum, benchmarking, competitor analysis, gdpr

management trainee

company: Scania

time period: 2013/07 - 2014/09

total work experience: 1 year 3 months

short description: The management trainee program gave me a comprehensive view of the operations of a big corporation. During my trainee year, I spent time in Scania's sales organization, at a distributor in Switzerland and Scania's R&D organization. I learned about the logistics business and the future of autonomous trucks. **stack**: sales, product development, autonomous vehicles, environmentally friendly, bio fuel, logistics business, transport operations, truck manufacturing